<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2026 VisorCraft LLC -->
<!-- SPDX-License-Identifier: GPL-3.0-only -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.visorcraft.LinSight</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <name>LinSight</name>
  <summary>Fast multi-GPU Linux system monitor</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      LinSight is a fast, beautiful, modular Linux system-monitoring dashboard.
      It shows live CPU, RAM, multi-GPU (NVIDIA + Intel xe), NVMe, and network
      sensors in a single Overview page, with a runtime plugin system for
      hardware that isn't covered out of the box.
    </p>
    <p>Key features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Subscription-driven sampling — sensors only run when something is watching</li>
      <li>Built-in support for NVIDIA NVML and Intel xe driver GPUs</li>
      <li>Per-NVMe SSD temperatures and bytes-read/written counters</li>
      <li>Per-interface network rx/tx counters and link state</li>
      <li>Always-on mode (opt-in): SQLite history + Prometheus exporter</li>
      <li>Remote dashboards over SSH-forwarded sockets</li>
      <li>Drop-in .so plugin support for new hardware</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.visorcraft.LinSight.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>linsight</binary>
    <binary>linsightd</binary>
    <binary>linsight-cli</binary>
  </provides>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/visorcraft/linsight</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/visorcraft/linsight/issues</url>
  <developer id="com.visorcraft">
    <name>VisorCraft LLC</name>
  </developer>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <categories>
    <category>System</category>
    <category>Monitor</category>
  </categories>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.13.0" date="2026-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>Multi-host view: save remote hosts, switch between them from the
        sidebar, and survive reconnects with automatic catalogue rebuild,
        subscription replay, and pump-interval replay.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.11.0" date="2026-06-11">
      <description>
        <p>Version bump to 1.11.0.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.10.0" date="2026-06-10">
      <description>
        <p>Process explorer page with sortable, filterable process table.
        SMART disk health sensors via udisks2. Alert event log with per-rule
        cooldown. Sensor snapshot caches for disk, net, fs, and system plugins.
        History charts with configurable retention pruning.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.9.0" date="2026-06-04">
      <description>
        <p>Hardening and performance update: client subscriptions are isolated
        and cleaned up on disconnect, history and Prometheus paths are bounded,
        CPU and memory sensors reuse short-lived snapshots, dashboard writes are
        more race-resistant, GUI daemon RPCs no longer block the QML thread, and
        CLI/tunnel behavior is aligned with the documented defaults.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.8.0" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>New application icon: the final LinSight mark (a layered hardware
        stack with a wavelength "L" and a thermometer accent) replaces the
        placeholder across all icon sizes and the in-app About and Credits
        pages. The in-app third-party license credits now list only genuine
        dependencies, and the documentation set was cleaned up.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.3" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Identity update: the application ID is now com.visorcraft.LinSight
        (matching the visorcraft.com domain), changed across the desktop entry,
        AppStream metadata, icons, Flatpak app-id and the window id. Users with
        a pinned launcher should re-pin LinSight after upgrading.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.2" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Maintenance update: the bundled third-party license notices were
        renamed to third-party-notices.md and regenerated against the current
        dependency set, and the translation catalogs were refreshed.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.1" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Packaging and release-automation update: continuous integration
        plus one-command multi-format release builds (portable tarball, Arch,
        Debian, Fedora, openSUSE, AppImage and Flatpak), with assorted
        packaging fixes and launcher icons in the distro packages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.0" date="2026-06-01">
      <description>
        <p>Security and robustness hardening: a panicking plugin is now
        isolated from the daemon instead of crashing it (plugin ABI v6); the
        remote tunnel's idle timeout no longer drops healthy long-lived
        sessions; and webhook alert targets are validated against SSRF.
        Out-of-tree plugins must be rebuilt against the v6 SDK.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.6.0" date="2026-05-31">
      <description>
        <p>Storage page nests mount points inside their physical disk as
        collapsible cards; GPU sections ordered by VRAM with unified "GPU
        VRAM" sensor naming; inode sensors skipped for filesystems that do
        not report them.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-05-25">
      <description>
        <p>All 10 spec phases shipped: daemon, CLI, Qt 6 / Kirigami GUI with sidebar, preset pages (Overview, GPUs, Storage, Network), canvas editor, alerts engine, Prometheus exporter, SQLite history, runtime .so plugin ABI v2 (stabby R-mirror types), and the linsight-tunnel mTLS bridge.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-05-24">
      <description>
        <p>Initial preview — Phase 1 through Phase 10 scaffolding.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
